漫威漫画
兰顿神父  克林顿教堂
Father Lantom. Clinton Church.
带他来明智吗
...bright idea to bring him in?
他是我们的信徒  玛姬  我还有什么选择
He's one of ours, Maggie. What other choice did I have?
市综合医院  打911
Metro-General maybe? Call 911.
他是个义警
He's a vigilante.
如果他去医院  会被警察逮捕的
If he goes to a hospital, the police will arrest him.
我是圣艾格尼丝孤儿院的玛姬·格蕾丝修女
This is Sister Maggie Grace at St. Agnes Orphanage--
这是马修  杰克·默多克的儿子
It's Matthew. Jack Murdock's son.
抱歉  我搞错了
I'm very sorry. I made a mistake.
去找钢丝钳  我们得帮他脱掉这衣服
Get wire cutters. We need to get him out of this suit.
去厨房把...拿来
Go to the kitchen and bring... we have.
-我能帮忙吗  -你做得够多了
- How can I help? - You've done enough.
你去哪了  艾丽卡
Where did you go, Elektra?
我们要死在这里了
We're gonna die here.
这就是活的感觉
This is what living feels like.
叫玛姬  告诉她他醒了
Get Maggie. Tell her he's awake.
艾丽卡
Elektra...
-你感觉怎么样  -别站起来
- How do you feel? - Don't try to stand up.
在哪  在哪
Where... where...
圣艾格尼丝  孤儿院
St. Agnes. The orphanage.
-多久了  -躺下  几周了
- How long? How long? - Lay down. Several weeks.
-她在哪  -谁
- Where is she? - Who?
艾丽卡  我
Elektra. I...
我不知道那是谁
I don't know who that is.
别起来
Stay in the bed.
-你会伤到自己的  -我的右耳  我不...
- You'll hurt yourself. - My right ear... I can't...
别动了
Just stop this right now!
该死的  马修
Damn it, Matthew!
我看不到了  我看不到了
Now I can't see. I can't see.
我看不到了
I can't see!
我看不到了  我看不到了
I can't see! I can't see!
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     夜魔草
校对     小酸奶
时间轴     吃土少女
后期     8T
总监     小酸奶
夜
魔
侠
第三季  第一集
马修
Matthew?
神父
Father.
我不知道你在
I didn't know you were there.
回到这里感觉很怪吧
Must feel strange to be back here.
你长大的地方
The place where you grew up.
我还没谢你呢  神父
I haven't thanked you yet, Father.
修女们应该能守口如瓶
Figured we could count on the nuns for their discretion.
她们知道你是谁
The nuns know who you are,
但玛姬修女让她们发誓保密了
but Sister Maggie swore them to secrecy.
不过她先骂了我一通
After she swore at me.
如果你想吃圣餐
If you want to take Communion...
我们可以...
we could, uh...
我们也可以就谈谈
Or we could just talk.
艾丽卡
Elektra...
大楼倒塌时我们就在一起
was with me when the building collapsed.
马修  艾丽卡数月前就去世了
Matthew, Elektra passed months ago.
-我们还给她举行了葬礼  -不  我记得
- We had a funeral for her. - No, shh... I remember.
我知道这听上去多疯狂  相信我  她真的在
I know it sounds crazy. I'm telling you, she was there.
我
I was...
就抱着她  然后...
holding on to her when...
不管怎样  大楼坍塌时被包围了
In any case, the building was surrounded when it collapsed.
没看到还有其他人跑出来了
Nobody else was seen getting out.
我很遗憾  马修
I am so sorry, Matthew.
你先忏悔
How about I take your confession
然后我们吃圣餐吧
and we go ahead with the Eucharist?
今天就不了  神父
Not today, Father.
我不怎么思考神秘事件  马修
Mystical thinking is not my bag, Matthew.
我可能是整个主教教区最理智的家伙了
Hell, I'm probably the most rational crank in the whole diocese,
但就连我也得承认  你的生还真是奇迹
but even I have to admit... it is a miracle you survived.
我们的对话  总是这个走向
Our conversations, they usually go this way.
我带着疑问来找你
I come to you with questions.
你告诉我你对上帝的理解
You tell me what you understand about God.
-工作所在吧  -我们今天歇歇吧
- Nature of the gig, I guess. - Give it a rest, shall we?
好
Sure.
我还会来的
I'll be around. I'll, uh...
等你想谈了
When you're ready to talk...
我们就谈
we'll talk.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
-你是谁  -跟你一样
- Who are you? - Same as you.
我在这里长大的
I grew up here.
我去  你是遭遇了什么
Damn! What happened to you?
生活
Life.
这个房间是不许进的
This room is off limits.
如果你们还能站得住
And if you're well enough to be up,
就可以回去上课
you're well enough to be in class.
抱歉  修女
Sorry, Sister.
又见面了  马修
Hello again, Matthew.
他们怕你
They're scared of you, huh?
你像他们这么大时也怕我
So were you when you were their age.
我得给你换纱布
I need to change your gauze.
你最好别傻乎乎地乱动
Preferably without you flailing around like an idiot.
我大概不该觉得惊讶
I guess I shouldn't be surprised by any of this.
你一直那么愤怒
You were always pissed off.
不过当时  你只是个失去了视力的男孩
Of course, back then, you were just a boy who lost his eyesight.
现在  你是地狱厨房的恶魔
And now, you're the Devil of Hell's Kitchen.
你听说过我
You've heard of me.
我住在孤儿院里  不是石头缝里
I live in an orphanage, not under a rock.
但我万万没想到会是我们的孩子
I just never imagined it'd be one of ours
穿着那件万圣节服装到处跑
running around in that Halloween costume.
我听说你做的那些事
The things I've heard you can do...
你是瞎子吧
You are blind, right?
你不是一直在装吧
You weren't just faking it the whole time?
恭喜
Congratulations.
终于被你逮到了
You finally caught me.
我不该问问吗
It's not a fair question?
是的  那起意外让我变成了瞎子
Yeah, the accident blinded me.
但它还让我的其他感官变敏锐了
It just also, uh, sharpened my other senses.
别担心  修女
Not to worry, Sister.
那些日子都过去了
Those days are behind me.
我右耳聋了
I'm deaf in my right ear,
现在连走去厕所都做不到
and I can't even walk to the bathroom now.
是啊  你伤得不轻
Yeah, well, you're pretty banged up.
你的脊椎  你的髋骨
Your spine, your hip.
后空翻可能是做不了了  但是
Well, the days of doing backflips might be over, but...
你还能站起来的
you'll get back on your feet.
现在你没危险了
Now that you're out of the woods...
你希望我走
You want me to go.
这里不是疗养院
It's not a convalescent home.
-我明白  -抱歉
- I understand. - I'm sorry.
我会想办法的
I'll figure something out.
你肯定至少有一个能让我帮你联系的人吧
There must be at least one person I can call for you.
没有
No.
没有人了
There's no one.
嗯  我已经提交那份报道了
Yeah. No, I filed that story already.
嗯  听着
Yeah! No, look...
那个啊  第五部分仍需要引述
Oh, that. No. Uh, part five still needs a quote.
我已经联系了几个人  很快就会有回复的
I put out a few lines. We'll get a bite soon.
嗯  好
Yeah, okay.
今天晚上前能弄好
Yeah, I'll have it for you by the end of the day.
好  嗯  再见
All right. Yeah. Bye.
该死
Shit.
我为什么要来啊  马特
What am I doing here, Matt?
我有件东西想给你看一看
I have something that I need you to see.
我是夜魔侠
I'm Daredevil.
散步散得怎么样
How was the walk?
我就是需要点空间
I just needed some space.
-这挺...  -当然  我懂
- It's a lot... - No, of course. I get it.
-请进  -谢谢
- Please, come in. - Thank you.
你看得到我吗
Can you see me?
不  并不能"看到"
No. No, not "see" exactly.
这不一样
It's different. It's, um...
我觉得这更好
I think it's better.
怎么"不一样"  怎么"更好"
"Different" how? "Better" how?
我可以感觉到关于你的一些东西
Well, I can sense things about you.
好吧  比如呢
Okay. Like what?
天呐  这很难解释
Oh, God. It's really hard to explain. Um...
说说看
Try me.
我知道你在来的路上停下过
I know that you stopped on the way over here.
去了我们最喜欢的印度餐馆
At our favorite Indian place.
可能是去回忆过去的
Probably it was a trip down memory lane,
因为没点餐  但点了酒
'cause you didn't eat but you did order a drink.
我闻得到你衣服上的咖喱味  还能
See, I can smell the curry on your clothes, and I can...
尝到你唇齿间的占美神
taste the Jameson's off your lips.
我知道告诉你这些让你不舒服了
I know that just telling you all that makes you uncomfortable...
因为我听得到你的心跳
'cause I can hear your heartbeat.
好丢人啊
This is humiliating.
凯伦  我该告诉你的  你有权生气
Karen, I should've told you. You have every right to be angry--
是啊  我是该非常生你的气
Yeah. I should be. I should be really angry at you.
但我曾看到你为我跟人打斗
But I watched you fight for me.
还是两次
Twice, actually.
你知道我还梦到过那个吗
You know I dreamed about that?
我在脑海里一遍遍地回放  我总...
I played it over in my mind again and again, and I keep...
我怎么能这么气一个救过我的人
How can I be this mad at someone who saved my life?
因为他是你的朋友
Because he's your friend
你在乎他  他却辜负了你的信任
and you care for him and he broke your trust.
别赞同我的话了  这样更糟
Yeah, well, stop agreeing with me. It's making it worse.
要我给你拿杯酒吗
Can I get you a drink?
他还知道我点头了
And he knows I nodded.
那拐杖什么的  只是演戏
So, the whole cane thing, it's just... an act?
是的
Yep.
抱歉
Sorry.
为什么
Why?
你为什么不信任我
Why didn't you trust me?
-你担心我批判你吗  -不是
- What, did you think I would judge you? - No.
我都没批判弗兰克  我为什么要说你
I didn't judge Frank. Why would I judge you?
或许你该批判弗兰克
Well, maybe you should judge Frank.
卡塞尔是个杀人犯  我不是
Castle's a killer. I'm not.
你并不总知道人们做事的动机
You don't always know what motivates people to do what they do.
是啊  但我能分辨得出谎言
Uh, yeah, but I know when they lie to me.
他们的心跳会泄密
Their heartbeats tell me.
我知道的是  我再不会骗你了
Here's what I know. I will never lie to you again.
我保证  好吗  随便问我什么
That's a promise. All right? Ask me anything.
你放在哪了
Where do you keep it?
橱柜里  箱子里
In the closet. In the chest.
我去
Holy shit.
现在怎么办
What... what happens now?
结束了  到此为止了  我要放下夜魔侠
It's over. That's it. I'm gonna leave Daredevil behind.
真的  就这么干脆吗
Really? You can just do that?
嗯
Yeah.
你和福吉差点骗我相信你是在酗酒
You know... you and Foggy had me almost convinced it was alcohol.
这样很说得通
It makes a lot of sense.
保密
You know, the secrecy,
抛弃社交和事业
abandoning social and professional commitments.
听上去像个瘾君子的行为
It... It certainly sounds like an addict.
不是那样的
Well, it's not like that.
那解释一下  因为我不是你
Help me out, then, because I'm not you.
我无法分辨你是不是在骗我
I can't tell if you're lying to me or not.
我不再需要他做我的一部分了
I don't need him to be a part of me anymore.
我也不想要他了
And I don't want him to be.
我想相信你
I want to believe you.
但夜魔侠未必是问题所在
I'm not so sure Daredevil is the problem.
该死
Shit.
凯伦
Karen?
凯伦  你在吗
Hey, Karen, you here?
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
嗯  没事  谢谢你来
Yeah, yeah, fine. Thanks for coming.
楼管放你进来的吗
Did the building manager let you in?
我以为你要把这里的东西都收拾了呢
I thought you said you were packing the place up.
是啊
Yeah.
记得我跟你说
Remember how I told you
要跟马特的房东商量  把这里租出去
I was gonna talk to Matt's landlord about letting his place go?
惊喜
Surprise.
怎么  你叫我帮你搬箱子时
What, so when you asked me to help you move boxes...
是啊  我骗了你
Uh, yeah, I lied.
其实  应该说算是耍了个诡计
I mean, technically it was more of, like, a ruse.
这样啊  你耍了诡计
Gotcha. You rused.
做记者改变了你  佩吉
Journalism has changed you, Page.
我来干什么
So what am I doing here?
对了  嗯
Right. Yeah. So...
等等  你住这儿了吗
Wait! Are you living here?
天呐  没有  我就是在付账单
No. God, no. I'm just paying the bills,
至少一部分  直到马特回来
or some of them, until Matt gets back, but, um...
马特被驱逐了
Matt's being evicted.
嗯  我需要你帮我
Yeah, I need you to help me
说服房东给我延期
convince his landlord to give me an extension.
-凯伦  -别  付两份房租实在是...
- Karen-- - No, just, carrying two rents is just...
我就欠了这一个月
I'm behind this month. That's all.
虽然说出来很让我伤心
As much as it hurts me to say this,
你是个记者
you're a reporter.
看看事实吧  一栋大楼坍塌在了马特身上
Look at the facts. A building fell on Matt. A big one.
从此他就杳无音信
And nobody's heard from him since.
马特死了
Matt's dead.
这是我第一次把这话说出来
That's the first time I've said that out loud.
我也不想接受
I don't want to accept it, either.
尤其还是我
Especially since I'm the one who...
-你知道的  -不
- you know... - No.
-把战衣带去给了他  -别
- ...brought him the Devil suit. - Hey, don't...
别那么怪自己
do that to yourself.
你知道那是他的选择  你带不带给他
You know that was his choice. He'd have gotten to that suit
他都会拿到战衣
whether you brought it to him or not.
我知道
I know.
但我还是忍不住
But it doesn't stop me from
希望我给他拿的是运动裤
wishing I'd brought him some sweatpants instead.
是啊  你说的都有道理  我...
You're right. Everything you're saying is making sense. I just...
我知道这不理智
I know it's irrational...
但我感觉得到
but I can just feel it.
他没死
He's not dead.
我会处理好这个  再多付一个月的房租
I'll take care of these and one more month's rent.
不了
No, no.
我们分吧  五五分
Let's just split 'em down the middle, 50-50.
好  但就到此为止了  好吗
Fine, but then that's it, okay?
那好吧
Come on, then.
这里远离孩子
It's away from the kids,
你可以在这里想待多久待多久
so you can stay here as long as you need.
但有点发霉了
Bit musty, though.
反正我也什么都闻不到
I can't smell anything anyway.
-那音乐  -上面的礼拜堂
- That music... - The chapel is right above us.
但那不是阿拉伯的吗
Yeah, but isn't that Arabic?
39街的清真寺水管爆了
The mosque on 39th had a pipe burst,
我们这几周要共用这里
so we're sharing our space for a few weeks.
地狱厨房照顾自己人
Hell's Kitchen takes care of its own.
就这里吧
This will have to do.
这里还是洗衣间  所以时不时会比较吵
It's also the laundry room, so it'll be noisy at times.
我可以拿聋的耳朵对着它嘛[谚语:充耳不闻]
I can always turn a deaf ear to it.
瞧  凡事都有好的一面
See? There's a bright side to everything.
-我需要你帮忙扶他上床  -嗯
- I'll need help getting him into bed. - Yeah.
不  我暂时不想躺下
No, I'd like to stay up a while.
那交给我吧  保罗
Then I can take it from here, Paul.
马修  如果你想谈
Matthew, if you wanna talk--
不想  谢谢
No. Thank you.
那么
So...
床就在你面前
the bed's right in front of you.
安修女帮你接了线
Sister Anne wired you up.
你按这个  我们在楼上就能听到  就会下来
If you press that, we'll hear you upstairs and come running.
因为我们没别的事可做了
Because we don't have anything better to do.
真有基督徒的风范
Very Christian of you.
愤怒  讥讽  顽固
Angry, sarcastic... and stubborn.
或许你是没有朋友
Maybe you don't have any friends.
有人曾对我说  战士就该是孤独的
Someone once told me that warriors were meant to be alone.
在乎他人只会削弱我
That caring for people would make me weak.
他听上去像是该来一发
Sounds like he needed to get laid.
这倒是个好解释
That actually explains a lot.
他说得没错
I mean, he was right, of course.
我关心了别人  就付出了代价
I let people in, I paid a price.
我再不会犯这样的错误了
I won't make that mistake again.
这是什么
What is this?
从仓库里翻出来的
Dug those out of storage.
之前一个读它们的可能也是你
You were probably the last one to read 'em.
我的圣经
My Bible.
好  我懂你意思了
All right. I get the hint.
我感觉
And I get the sense
你对楼上大佬[上帝]有点意见呢
things are complicated with you and the guy upstairs.
不  没有
No. Not at all.
如果要说
If anything, I'd say
我们算是终于知道对彼此的立场了
we finally know where we stand with each other.
"乌斯地有一个人"
"There was a man from the land of Uz..."
《约伯记》
Book of Job.
没错
The Book of Job.
讲述了上帝的完美仆人  约伯
The story of God's perfect servant, Job.
他每天清晨起来祈祷
He prayed every day at dawn,
跪在地上  深深叩拜
with his knees on the ground, his face in the dirt.
杀十只羊  为他的十个孩子
Slaughtered ten goats, one for each of his children,
烧了羊  献祭上帝
and burned them at the altar in God's honor.
在上帝的士兵里  约伯是最忠诚的
Of all of God's soldiers, Job, he was the most loyal.
这故事我知道  马修
I know the story, Matthew.
那你就知道接下来的故事
Then you know what happens next.
上帝冷血地杀了他的十个孩子
God murdered all ten of his children in cold blood.
还烧毁了约伯的土地
Scorched every inch of Job's land.
鞭笞了他的身体  直到他血肉模糊
Lashed at his body till his skin was covered in bloody welts.
上帝给他的
God rained shit and misery
完美仆人带去了腥风血雨
on the life of his most perfect servant.
但约伯还是不肯诅咒他
And still... Job would not curse him.
知道我明白了什么吗
You know what I realized?
约伯是个怂包
Job was a pussy.
我曾经也是  修女
You see, that was me, Sister.
我自愿受苦
I suffered willingly.
我献出了
I gave my, uh...
我的汗水  血和皮肉  从不抱怨
sweat and blood and skin without complaint.
因为我也相信我是上帝的战士
Because I too believed I was God's soldier.
今后不会了
Well, not anymore.
我现在只在暗处行事
I am what I do in the dark now.
我只为自己流血
I bleed only for myself.
你没听我说
You weren't listening.
那些恶意的话我都听到了
I heard every spiteful word.
你现在或许恨上帝  但他不会恨你
You might hate God right now, but the feeling is not mutual.
不  我不恨他
No, I don't hate him.
我只不过是见识到了他的真面目
I've just seen his true face, is all.
而且  我曾经有朋友  有生活
And, for the record, I had friends. I had a life.
我在乎他人
I care about people,
我选择让他们相信我死了  就是出于在乎
and I'm choosing to let them believe that I'm gone because I am.
我不是约伯
I'm not Job.
我现在看清自己的真相了
And I know my truth now.
什么真相
What truth?
在这个上帝面前
Well, that in front of this God...
我宁可作为恶魔死去
I'd rather die as the Devil
也不想作为马特·默多克活着
than live as Matt Murdock.
安静
Quiet!
我们有好消息  菲斯克先生
We have good news, Mr. Fisk.
你的上诉在如我们所讨论的那样进行
Your appeal is proceeding as discussed.
消息
News.
应该是有新信息的
That implies new information.
直接从那里说起吧
Let's start there.
我们要提醒你  我们只是信使
We'll remind you, we're only the messengers.
我们已经在尽力帮她了
We've been doing everything we can to help her.
但玛丽安娜女士的归来
But there have been some setbacks
遭遇了一些挫折
regarding Ms. Marianna's return.
这会比我们的预期复杂
It's going to be more complicated than we anticipated.
怎么说
How so?
联邦政府决定起诉她从犯罪
The federal government has decided to charge her as an accessory.
如果他们在海外找到她  或是她回到美国本土
If they locate her overseas or she sets foot on US soil,
她都将面临指控  进监狱
she'll face prosecution and prison.
这样啊
I see.
走吧
Leave.
你在干什么
What on earth are you doing?
摔倒
Falling.
我带了东西给你
I brought you something.
是食物吗  我闻不到
Is it food? I can't smell anything.
热棕榈酒
A hot toddy.
能打开你的鼻窦
It'll help open your sinuses.
谢谢
Thank you.
你得坚持服用这个
And you need to keep taking these.
是热的  但
Well, it's hot, but...
我还是只能尝到血和灰的味道
I still can't taste anything but blood and ash.
干杯
Cheers.
药和酒  最好的现代医药
Pills and liquor, modern medicine at its finest.
行了  你个机灵鬼
Easy, smart-ass.
你要现代医药  门在前面
If you want modern medicine, the door's straight ahead.
-反正也无所谓了  -就要这精神
- It doesn't matter anyway. - That's the spirit.
耳鸣怎么样了
How's the buzzing?
没有好转
Not getting better.
耐心点
Give it time.
你被打得那么惨  到处都肿了
After the beating you took, everything's swollen.
或许等肿消了  你的听力能恢复
Maybe your hearing will come back when it goes down.
或等你不再犯浑了  它就会恢复
Or maybe it'll come back when you take your head out of your ass.
你是喝了多少
How many of these did you have?
你说的话
What you said...
关于宁可作为恶魔死去
about rather dying as the Devil
也不要作为马特·默多克活着
than living as Matt Murdock...
我想告诉你  我觉得你是个英雄
I just want you to know that I think you're a hero.
藏在这里  自怨自艾
Hiding down here, feeling sorry for yourself.
就在外面
I mean, just out back,
住着一群孤儿
there's an orphanage full of kids
他们失去了一切  所有人
who've lost everything and everyone.
有些残疾了  比你当初糟多了
Some of them are disabled, much worse off than you ever were.
他们还是在努力生活
And they're still trying to make the most out of life,
那些小懦夫
the little cowards.
好了  行了
Okay. All right.
而你呢  拥有上帝赋予你的一切天赋
And here you are, with all the gifts God gave you.
帅气  聪明  有法律学位
Handsome, smart, a law degree,
还有在乎你的人
and people who care about you.
你却勇敢地放弃了
And you're bravely giving up.
谢谢了
Well, you know, thank you...
感谢你的严厉教导  修女
for the tough love, Sister.
还有你对上帝和世界简单得可爱的观点
And your charmingly simplistic view of God and the world.
我感谢你为我做的一切  真的
I appreciate everything you've done for me, I do,
但千万别以为你了解
but don't for a second think you know
我或我的生活
anything about me or my life.
我做了30年修女
I've been a nun for 30 years.
我听的出什么是自怨自艾
I know self-pity when I hear it.
好啊
Okay, good.
你父亲在这里很有名
Your father was famous around here.
我看过他打拳
I saw him fight.
我见过他被打倒很多次
I saw him go down many times.
但他总会站起来
But he never stayed down.
怎么回事
What in God's name have...
-感觉到了吗  -什么
- Feel that? - Feel what?
我们下面有三条地铁线路
Three subway lines run beneath us.
在任何时刻
At any given time,
都有六列地铁在振动地面
there are six different trains vibrating the ground.
刚刚是E号线
That was the E train.
是吗
Was it now?
你带来了食物
You brought food.
是的  我带了
I did. I brought you some...
诺娜餐馆的牛肉饺子  不错啊
Beef ravioli from Nonna's. Nice.
臭显摆吧你
Now you're just showing off.
他想知道他还能做到
He wants to know that he's still got it.
我不喜欢这样
I am not comfortable with that idea.
这你还不喜欢
Now you're uncomfortable?
身体愈合  心灵也会愈合
Heal the body, and the spirit will follow.
是倒过来的
It's the other way around.
他需要这个
He needs this.
而且这是唯一让他下了床的事
It's the only damn thing that's gotten him out of bed.
你就去吧
So please just do it.
谢谢你成全我
Thanks for making this happen.
手应该用来做上帝的工作
Hands should be used for God's work.
是吗  所以他才把我变成这样吗
Yeah? That's why he made me this way?
不是  所以他才发明了拳击
No. That's why he made boxing.
-手套  -先戴头盔
- Gloves? - Helmet first.
不行  会影响我的
No, I can't. It'll throw me off.
-别犯傻  -修女  听我说
- Don't be an idiot. - Sister, listen to me.
要成功  我得能感受到  听到一切
For this to work, I have to feel and hear everything.
记住我们说好的  嘴巴闭牢
Now, remember the deal. Keep your mouth shut.
比念祷文要强
Beats the Hail Marys.
你要我打个瞎子
You want me to hit a blind guy?
好了
All right.
停  暂停
Cut! Time!
-没事吧  -嗯  我没事
- You good? - Yeah, I'm good.
该死  他出拳好狠
Damn. He hits hard.
亲眼看到  真是震撼
It's really something. To see it with my own eyes.
不  感觉不对  我像是在水下
No. Something feels off. It feels like I'm underwater.
-或许该停下  -不不
- Maybe we should stop. - No, no, no.
开始吧  我们再来
Ding-ding. Let's go again.
马修
Matthew?
Matthew!
另一个人更惨
You should see the other guy.
不管怎样
For what it's worth...
你真的很了不起
you were incredible.
谢谢
Thank you.
修女  我
Sister, I...
你脑袋拧到后面去了吗  那就为我戴
Did your head spin around? Then wear it for me.
你对我真好
You've been very kind to me.
可不是呢
I have, haven't I?
还很耐心呢
And patient. Very, very patient.
别说出去  否认人家会觉得我心软了
Don't tell anyone. They'll think I've gone soft.
不  那应该是不会的
No. I don't think there's any danger of that.
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
我以前会给爸爸缝针
I used to sew up my dad.
你缝得非常好
And your stitches are perfect.
在这里有的是练习的机会
Well, there's plenty of practice around here.
没事吧
Everything okay?
嗯  没事
Yeah. It's fine.
我得回楼上去了
I just have to get back upstairs.
你不会来跟我做弥撒吧
I don't suppose there's any hope you'd come to Mass with me?
下次吧
Maybe next time.
那我等你了
I'll hold you to that.
别碰他  你干什么呢  爸爸
Get off of him! Hey! What are you doing? Dad!
爸爸
Dad!
救命  放开  救命
Help! Get off! Help!
天呐  爸爸  爸爸
Oh, my God! Dad! Dad...
撑住  我们带你去医院
Stay with me. We'll get you to the hospital.
走吧
Come on!
混蛋  这本来不关你事
Hey, asshole, this was none of your business.
来吧
Come on.
我们该杀了这混蛋
We should kill this son of a bitch.
不  放过他吧
Nah, man. Leave him.
等等
Hold on.
上帝饶恕我
God forgive me.
别管他了  我们走吧
Leave him. Let's get out of here.
我们真的没火鸡了  你没去趟熟食店吗
We seriously out of turkey? You didn't swing by the deli?
我去了
I did, actually.
我在收银台付款时  遇到了点麻烦
I ran into a little payment snafu at the register.
我本想在派对结束后再提的
I wanted to make it through the party before I brought it up.
你用的哪张卡  红维萨吗
Uh, which card did you use? The red Visa, right?
当然是的
Yeah, of course. Yeah.
爸爸
Hey, Dad.
小寿星来了
There's the birthday goon!
玛茜·萨维那问你是不是把晚饭做糊了
Masi Savina wanted to know if you're ruining dinner.
什么
Excuse me?
她又要损我的厨艺
Is she trying to undermine my culinary talents again?
过来
Get over here.
给你看看大厨的手艺
Let me show you how a master chef does his thing.
看啊
Check this out.
看到我在做什么了吗  萨米
See what I'm doing here, Sami?
这叫"剥"
This is a technique called "skimming."
相当有难度
High degree of difficulty.
看
Ta-da!
-你来啊  -好
- Wanna do the honors? - Yes.
你用的真是红维萨吗
Are you positive you used the red Visa?
我上周付过的  应该没问题
I paid that one last week. That one should be good.
我试了红维萨  蓝维萨  银万事达
I tried the red Visa, the blue Visa, the silver Mastercard...
我还刷了借书证
I even tried my library card.
没事的
It's okay.
我们以前也不是没遇到过
Nothing we haven't handled before.
请容我说两句
If I could have the floor for a minute?
如果你们还不知道
If you haven't heard by now,
虽然尼阿都在屋顶上大喊过了
despite Nihar shouting it from the rooftops...
我勇敢的嫂子  癌症已经痊愈
...my courageous sister-in-law is now 100% cancer-free.
我们知道你过得很艰难
We know that it hasn't been easy for you,
你面临了那么多的困难
with all the obstacles you've faced.
一遍遍地被保险拒赔
Being denied insurance over and over again.
那些混蛋机构就那么欺负你
Those asshole institutions running you over like a tank.
总之
Anyway...
今晚  我们庆祝
tonight, we celebrate.
这杯敬你  桑薇  干杯  干杯
This one's for you, Saanvi. Cheers. Cheers.
没有你我们做不到的  弟弟
We couldn't have done it without you, brother.
别
No, please don't.
真的  雷
I'm serious, Ray.
是你俩在辛苦  我不过是签了几张支票
You two did the work. I just wrote a few checks.
你在这儿干什么呢  孩子
What are you doing out here, bug?
大家都在吃饭  我们在等着点蜡烛呢
Everyone's eaten. We're waiting to light the candles.
我不想吃了
I don't think I want any.
不吃蛋糕  他不想吃蛋糕
No cake? He doesn't want any cake.
他肯定是出大毛病了
There must be something seriously wrong with him.
真的  孩子  怎么了
No, seriously, bug. What's up?
我们为什么非要今天办家庭派对
I don't know why we had to have our family party today.
我说了  里奇·托马斯请了朋友过去玩
I told you, Ricky Thomas is having friends over.
我本可以去他家在地下室里玩打保龄球
I could be at his house, glow bowling in his basement right now.
托马斯家地下室有保龄球馆
The Thomases have a bowling alley in their basement?
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
等到了夏天
Come the summer,
你会是那个开大派对的人
you're the one who's gonna be throwing mad parties,
因为今年我们绝对建泳池
because the pool is definitely happening this year.
-真的吗  -当然的
- Really? - You bet.
等到六月  我就要把你丢下跳水台了
I'm gonna be tossing your butt off the diving board by June.
我们进去  吃点蛋糕吧
Now, what do you say we go inside, throw back some cake?
-好  -好吗
- Okay. - Yeah?
-泳池啊  -别
- The pool, huh? - No, don't.
娜狄娅说她的一个文学助教上周辞职了
Listen, Nadia said one of her literacy tutors quit last week.
或许我晚上可以去中心上几小时课
Maybe I could pick up some evening hours at the center--
你不能去做兼职  我们走过这条路了
You're not getting another job. We've been down this road before.
我知道  雷  但我想不到别的办法了
I know, Ray, but I can't see another way out.
我会解决的
I'll fix this.
我会解决一切的
I'll fix everything.
我九点还跟萨拉查有约
I've got a nine o'clock with Salazar,
除非你能长话短说
so unless you got something quick...
萨拉查被叫去市中心了
Salazar just got called downtown.
那你随意吧
Well, make yourself at home.
谢谢
Thanks.
主管特工
塔米·哈特利
我的绩效评估
My performance review.
那是月底的事呢  是吧
That's not until the end of the month, correct?
我想提前做  现在就做
I'd like it moved up. I'd like to do it now.
这可做不到  雷
That's a tall order, Ray.
绩效评估可不是能随便安排的事
Performance review isn't the kind of thing we shuffle around.
那为什么我的评估被延迟两次了
Then how come mine's been deferred twice now?
你让我得不到我应得的
You're denying me the advancement opportunities
晋升机会
that I have rightfully earned.
不是局里  是你的意思
No, not the Bureau. You.
你为什么要这么对我  我不知道
Now, why you'd do something like that to me, I don't have a clue.
但我或许该向就业机会平等委员提交投诉了
But maybe it's time I file a complaint with the EEO.
是啊
You're right.
你的评估是被推迟了
Your reviews have been deferred
而原因并非日程或改组
for reasons having nothing to do with scheduling or restructuring
或我当时编的任何胡话
or whatever bullshit I fed you at the time.
是因为我想保护你
It's because I'm trying to protect you.
保护我
Protect me?
你知道你的信用分数是多少吗
Do you have any idea what your FICO score is?
557  你的信用分数是557
557. Your FICO score is 557.
是不太好  我知道...
So it's not stellar. You know, I--
你债务缠身  因此你容易成为策反对象
You're buried in debt, and that makes you a recruitment target.
局里有政策
It's Bureau policy
不能提升有这种把柄的人
not to promote someone with that level of vulnerability.
我的情况很特别  你很清楚
My circumstances were exceptional, and you know that.
-我嫂子病了  -我非常遗憾
- My sister-in-law was sick and I-- - I am sorry for that.
三年半
Three and a half years.
我已经三年半没涨工资了
I haven't had a pay bump in three and a half years.
我知道这不对
I know it's wrong.
我知道
I know.
你是个好探员
You're a fine agent.
但我帮不了你
But I can't make this happen for you.
除非你先处理好你的财务状况
Not until you fix your finances.
但是这样
But look...
正好你在
while I got you here...
该你去了
your number's up.
好啊  好时机
Nice. Nice timing.
我知道这任务很扯
It's a shit errand. I get it.
我们每个月都去找他
We talk to this guy every month,
他每个月都什么不说
and every month he gives us nothing.
这一路上风景挺好的
It's a nice drive, though.
菲斯克先生  我是联邦调查局的
Mr. Fisk, I'm Special Agent Ray Nadeem
特别探员雷·纳迪姆
with the Federal Bureau of Investigation.
联调局想请你协助...
The FBI would like your assistance with...
你直接叫我去吃屎吧
Let's cut to the part where you tell me to eat shit,
我们也不用浪费彼此的时间了
so we can stop wasting each other's time, huh?
告诉我  纳迪姆特别探员
Tell me, Special Agent Nadeem...
你生命里可有你挚爱的
do you have anyone in your life who you love so much,
会不惜一切保护的人吗
you'd do anything to protect them?
你是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
我犯下过不少错误
I have made many mistakes.
但我接受我因此要还的债
But I accept the debt I'm paying because of them.
但我不能接受的
But what I will not accept...
是我所爱的女人也要为此还债
is that the woman that I love should have to pay for them, too.
我愿不惜一切保护她
I would do anything to protect her.
不惜一切
Anything.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是什么意思
What is it you're saying?
我想做个交易
I want to make a deal.